

Federico Irarrazaval

FULL STACK DEVELOPER



About me

I am proactive and disciplined.

My academic and employment experience have always oriented me to deliver customer-oriented and high quality products and services.

Technologies

JavaScript | Typescript | Node.js Express.js | Koa.js | Fastify | MongoDB Mongoose | API REST | JSON | HTML React | Redux | CSS | Chakra UI Bootstrap | Git | GitHub | Railway Heroku | Vercel | Vtex IO

Skills

- Team work | SCRUM methodology
- Developed soft skills
- Advanced English proficiency (C2 Proficient)

Hobbies

I enjoy my reading, as well as technology and gamming.

I am also interested in sports. Currently practicing archery.

Contact Me









June 1, 2024

Professional Experience

ITGlobers - Back End Engineer (Feb. 2023 - Present)

Back end developer for marketplaces and e-commerce projects working with Typescript, Node.js, Express.js, Koa.js, API's, and VTEX IO. Notable projects include:

- Development of a service to synchronize order statuses between the ecommerce platform and the client's ERP system.
- Development and migration to documents uploading using Google Cloud Storage buckets with PHP.
- Audit of architecture, integrations, and custom applications for e-commerce optimization.
- Development of integration solutions between VTEX e-commerce and payment provider systems. Contributed as a back-end developer and leader of the payments development team.
- Integration of JIRA with Google Forms for workflow automation.
- Design and development of a solution for data synchronization between two storage systems.

Academic Experience

Bootcamp Full Stack Web Developer

Henry, 2022

1000 hours of courses and practice with the following technologies: Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, API REST, React, Redux, HTML and CSS I collaborated in the following projects:

4 weeks development experience under SCRUM methodology. I collaborated as full stack developer.

Kinema is a movie and tv shows streaming website built with the following technologies: Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Moongose, React, Redux, Chakra UI, CSS, Cloudinary, Firebase, Stripe, Email.js, Railway and Vercel.

Kinema was selected by Henry's bootcamp among the top 4 projects of the course.

4 weeks development experience.

G&B is a videogame browser website built following clean architecture principles and with the following technologies: Typescript, Javascript, fastify, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, React, Redux and CSS. Deployed with Railway and Vercel.

Relevant Programming Courses

- Course "Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2)." Platzi, 2024
- Course "Roles and Security with IAM on AWS." Platzi, 2024
- Course "Networking, Governance and Machine Learning on AWS." Platzi, 2023
- Course "Compute, storage and databases on AWS." Platzi, 2023
- Course "Introduction to AWS". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Introduction to Cloud Computing". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Typescript OOP and asynchrony". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Node. and authentication with passport and jwt". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Node.js practice: Authentication". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Typescript. Advanced types and functions". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Typescript. Fundamentals". Platzi, 2023
- Course "Backend with Node.js: REST API with express.js". Platzi, 2023

Employment Background

Sr. Attorney

Baker McKenzie, 2015 - 2022

Labour & Employment law advise and litigation for local and foreign companies. Led paralegals and junior attorneys teams.

Academic Background

Postgraduate and Specialization in Labor Law

Pontifical Catholic University of Argentina, 2016 - 2020

Law Degree

Pontifical Catholic University of Argentina, 2006 - 2014

Bachelor's Degree

Los Molinos School, 1994 - 2006